Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ vanshikamehta (LinkedIn) vanshichats.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Marketing Social Media Social Media Marketing

Languages

French (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Advanced Branding
Conversational Marketing Certified
UX Foundations: Storytelling
Stories Every Leader Should Tell
Online Marketing Fundamentals

Vanshika Mehta

Branding & Storytelling Consultant to Startups and SMB's | 'Not A Linkedin Expert' since 2017 | Always witty, Sometimes funny | Solopreneur Est. Jan 2020 | HBR Ascend Member | India

Summary

TI;DR Version

| Brand Strategy, Copywriting and Strategic Communications, Networking and Event Planner, LinkedIn pro user since 2017 |

Now for the long(er) version-

Is it strange to start an 'about me' thanking your school and parents for what today is your passion and, career path?

Absolutely not. Give credit where it's due.

Being born and brought up in Dubai, English was my first language; by my parents and school.

What started off as weekly spelling tests when I was between the age group of 5-8, grew into me becoming an avid reader, which finally transpired into attaining an A grade in my GCE O Level examination and 82% in my TOEFL.

Fun fact: French was my second language and Arabic was my third.

During the summer hols, I was lucky to have travelled the world; I've been to London, Paris, Kenya, Belgium, Bangkok, Singapore, Malaysia, Florida, New York and a couple others I'd need to surf through my albums to remember.

Right before I graduated, I knew I had to take on challenges that would help me push the comfort zone envelope:

> I conceptualized, managed and ran two-yearly charity concert-style events the same title; 'Cambridge For Charity' in 2009 and 2010. The charities we donated to were The Red Crescent Society in 2009 and The Dubai Autism Center in 2010.

> I attended the Global Young Leaders Conference 2010, held annually in USA. I was amongst 500+ of the brightest minds globally.

After a gap year, I went on to pursue my undergraduate degree at Northeastern University and graduated in 2016 December with a BSc. Marketing and Management.

While I was studying, I was very active within communities, at school and outside

I volunteered via Big Sister Association, Boston for over 2 years I danced on stage at almost every Nataraj and Dance For Me I attended sessions hosted by the NU Entrepreneur's Club I travelled to parts of California, Arizona, Illinois, Wisconsin, Connecticut, New Hampshire, Maine, New York.

It was an extremely fulfilling, opportunity-grabbing, exciting, deep-learning experience at Northeastern University in Boston, while I was there 2011-2016.

In 2018, I moved to India, and, it was quite the change! Since moving here and writing this today (Jan 2020)...

I've worked in eCommerce, Fintech and, Design using my skills to build their brand and strengthen communications.

If you see an opportunity for us to work together, or, banter over anything brand/communications, please reach out to me on :: vanshi.mehta@gmail.com

Or, go ahead and book a slot: https://calendly.com/

vanshimehta/15min

Experience

Self

Brand and Communications Strategist and Consultant January 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months)

I help startups and brands tell their true story, with a strategy, alongside appropriate content, for their audience/user persona.

Things I'm skilled at:

Communication strategy

Content strategy

Content writing

Content marketing

Linkedin Marketing

Industries I've worked with in the past:

Tech

SaaS

EdTech

HR

FinTech

Design

Want to chat about a project? Reach out to me here!

PeakPerformer

Community Coordinator

August 2020 - Present (1 month)

Digifynd

Content and Community Lead

May 2020 - Present (4 months)

⇒ Creating content to build awareness and interest in Digifynd's activities.

Additionally, I am responsible for managing their online community.

My goal is to create memorable online experiences via the webinars we are hosting with market leaders.

Sqrrl Fintech

Brand Storyteller

June 2019 - November 2019 (6 months)

- ⇒ Building audience and transactional customers via a multi-channel approach
- Upgraded customer-facing emails and push notifications on CleverTap to ensure brand language

is maintained

- Crafted communication to be used for retention purposes along with Content Lead and Growth Lead
- Assisted with UX content writing on new pages that were created for insurance and lending
- Generated an opportunity with TapChief's 75K professionals to host a webinar session
- Advocated for and pioneered podcast presence for Sqrrl on the Paisa
 Vaisa Podcast winner of
 Best Business Podcast, 2019
- Established a thought-leadership Linkedin strategy for the CEO to build a stronger corporate

reputation. 30,000 post views recorded on Yourstory, Tech 30 announcement

onething Content Writer and Events Lead January 2019 - May 2019 (5 months) India

PostFold

Community Manager April 2018 - December 2018 (9 months)

- ⇒ Engaging community via brand collaborations, events, content, and email correspondence
 - Led 3 experiential events for audiences, 30-150 people.
- * Salsa Night in collaboration with The Wine Company, Moving Souls and gifting partners
- * Style Your Way in collaboration with Innov8, Merry Käufer and domain experts
- * Do Good Diwali in collaboration with SimplyBlood, Literacy India, Friendicoes and finally, Robin
 Hood Army
- Initiated brand collaborations with 4 co-working spaces and food delivery vendors

- Interviewed and developed content about 3 distinguished individuals from DelhiNCR for the blog section PFAdmires
- Managed weekly email workflow and upgraded email content and visuals for communications sent via MailChimp

Washify Services LLC
Digital Engagement Success Specialist
September 2017 - January 2018 (5 months)

- ⇒ Launched and directed the marketing strategy for existing clients
 - Managed 5 clients' onboarding onto social media platforms.
- Created a content calendar for each client, ensuring the language resonated with the brand.

QuotaFactory
Inside Sales Consultant
March 2017 - July 2017 (5 months)
Framingham, MA

- \Rightarrow Consistently supported outbound sales efforts for clients within technology solutions and staffing.
- Researched and prospected 60+ leads daily using effectual sales strategies through LinkedIn Sales Navigator and CRM System SalesForce.
- Coordinated with the Director of Business Development to identify leads, report on weekly progress and gain feedback to increase performance and overall productivity.

Dell EMC

Social Media Strategist / Conference Planner January 2016 - June 2016 (6 months) Hopkinton, USA

⇒ Responsible for audience management, engagement and reporting through Lanyon and Sprinklr (Facebook) alongside providing quality customer service for the company's 10,000+ attendee user conference.

- Spearheaded Facebook campaigns using Sprinklr by creating engaging content thereby increasing followers by 8% alongside supporting the ecosystem.
- Analyzed and reported on KPI's using Omniture and Excel (Vlookup, pivot tables) to demonstrate weekly progress on attendance for executive reporting.
- Engaged in attendee management exercises through Lanyon to ensure event success on site for the 10,000+ attendees.
- Researched and delivered a presentation to executives on technology conferences, identifying areas of strength and presented improvements.
- Other responsibilities: customer service, PowerPoint presentations, vendor management and sourcing.

MassEcon

Digital Communications Specialist / Event Prog. Manager July 2013 - December 2013 (6 months)

Watertown, MA

- ⇒ Responsible for member engagement through social media and emails for hosted events.
- Marketed pertinent Massachusetts business news and MassEcon events to audience through Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn using Hootsuite.
- Developed monthly newsletters using InDesign and Photoshop for distribution to mailing lists via Constant Contact and uploaded to website via WordPress.
- Liaised with attendees, vendors and venues for 13 events with 30-300 attendees.
- Researched and consolidated contenders for Team Massachusetts Economic Impact Awards using online journals and news articles.
 - Other responsibilities: project management and networking.

Education

Northeastern University

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Management and Marketing · (2011 - 2016)

Cambridge For Charity

Special Event Planner · (2009 - 2010)

Cambridge High School, Dubai, United Arab Emirates

A Level · (2008 - 2010)